techexplorist.com 2018-12-28

# Privacy Policy - Tech Explorist

### 

Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. At Tech Explorist, we want to make your experience online satisfying and safe.

This Privacy Policy governs your use of TechExplorist and its network including its website (techexplorist.com), any subdomains of the website, mobile site, app, and APIs.

## What we collect?

We collect information from you when you register on our site, subscribe to our newsletter, fill out a form or comment on the site. When registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name, e-mail address or website URL.

Furthermore, whenever you visit our Website, we may collect non-identifying information from you, such as your weblog data, your IP address, user agent, referring URL, browser, operating system, cookie information, and Internet Service Provider; operating system and device type; your location, and the language option you choose in your device. Without additional legal requests or records from a third party, this information alone cannot usually be used to identify you. The information we collect from you to the extent that it is private and disclosed only in accordance with our [Terms of Service](https://www.techexplorist.com/terms/) and/or this Privacy Policy.

## Cookies:

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

Techexplorist.com uses cookies to enable our servers to recognize your web browser and gather information on the frequency of your visiting the Website, share Content, and otherwise use our Service. This Privacy Policy covers our use of cookies only and does not cover the use of cookies by third parties. We do not control or monitor when or how third parties place cookies on your computer.

For example, If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

## What do we use your information for?

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * **To personalize your experience:**  
Your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs.
  * **To improve our website:**  
We continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.
  * **To improve customer service:**  
Your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs.
  * **To send periodic emails:  **  
The email address you provide may be used to send you information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

Additionally, we use your personal information to provide and improve our Services, provide you with a personalized experience on our sites, provide you with personalized advertising and marketing, and to detect, prevent, mitigate and investigate fraudulent or illegal activities. Throughout the course of the provision of our Service to you, we may delegate our authority to collect, access, use, and disseminate your information. For this reason, you hereby agree that for every authorization which you grant to us in this Privacy Policy, you also grant to any third party that we may hire, contract, or otherwise retain the services of for the purpose of operating, maintaining, repairing, or otherwise improving or preserving our website or its underlying files or systems. You also agree not to hold us liable for the actions of any of these third parties.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

We use third-party tools for audience measurement on our websites. We currently use Google Analytics and Facebook Pixel for this purpose. Google Analytics and Facebook Pixel use cookies to anonymously and in an aggregate report on visits to our websites. We do not combine the information collected through the use of these tools with personally identifiable information. Further information concerning the terms and conditions of use and data privacy can be found at www.google.com/analytics/terms. The Facebook privacy policy is available at www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation

## Who we share your data with?

Techexplorist.com may share or release your information in response to a request from a government agency or a private litigant for legal purposes. You agree that we may disclose your information to a third party where we believe, that it required doing so for the purposes of a civil action, criminal investigation, or other legal matters. You release us from any damages that may arise from or relate to the share or release of your information to a request from law enforcement agencies or private litigants.

## Do we disclose any information to outside parties?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise, transfer your personally identifiable information to outside parties. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

### Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We, therefore, have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

### Online Privacy Policy Only

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.

### Terms and Conditions

Please also visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website at  _[https://www.techexplorist.com](https://www.techexplorist.com/)._

### Your Consent

By using our site, you consent to our online privacy policy.

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page.

This policy was last modified on May 24, 2018.

### Contacting Us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us here.
